I'll show you what this is.
Quiet on the set,
quiet please,
first position please,
rolling, action.
Hello everyone and welcome back to another edition of Directors Cut.
I am joined here with Mr. Gulam Subhani.
Hey Marco.
Alright, and Catherine is here as well.
Hi.
And as Gulam said, my name is Marco and today we're gonna be talking about
a great film, one of the three parts of a really great trilogy
called The Lord of the Rings by J.R.R. Tolkien so it was books from forever ago that were recently
made into a three-part movie right so the first part is called long movies very long and the first
part is called The Fellowship of the Ring it's called The Fellowship of the Ring because a
fellowship is like a group of people who come together for a common cause and in this case the
common cause is the fighter of good against evil the fight of good against evil very generally or
getting rid of the ring of power which was forged in Mordor all right so that's basically the story
there is a ring that was forged from like lava right or some from the depths of hell or something
yeah and horror and evil and all things bad all things bad yeah darkness all right so and this
ring was forged in order to do what to control the world to have power absolute power okay it
makes the person immortal doesn't it it doesn't it makes them the supreme ruler so there's other
rings in the world but none are as powerful as the one ring oh yeah this one ring is the most
powerful it has it has control over all the other rings so it's like the main and where are the other
rings the kings of men have nine of them and the dwarfs have seven of them and the elves have three
of them all right so uh and then this one ring controls everyone yes all right so basically
the ring is evil so whoever wears it kind of becomes more evil or obsessed with power and
control right it takes over you it takes over yeah so the movie is about the battle of good and
evil on middle earth which is the place where this takes place but it's also about the battle
of good and evil in one person's soul because whoever has the ring really has to deal with this
fight inside of them so it's kind of a an internal fight of ambition of of controlling your your
impulse to become better or immortal or something like that it is and the special thing about this
movie is that it doesn't feature a human being man you know powerful it's it features a hobbit
hobbits are special creatures so a hobbit is like a very small small person right a small hairy
big-footed kind of dull person they kind of like elves i think but maybe bigger than elves chubbier
and they're they're like like humans so they can die elves can't die so um what is the name
of the main character of the hobbit that carries the ring furotto furotto furotto Baggins right
and his uncle gave him the ring his uncle Bilbo Bilbo Baggins Bilbo Baggins gave him the ring
all right and you also have a different race apart from the hobbits you have the as you mentioned
the elves the elves have long pointy ears and white hair and they're very beautiful and you
know pure looking and they're immortal right they're immortal and they can kind of do spells and
magic and stuff all right and then you also have the elves dwarfs dwarfs and you also have the
dwarfs yeah and they live in the caves and they're great miners and builders and they're also really
small and stocky okay and uh and then you have a wizard in there as well yeah what's his name
kind of like merlin he's kind of like merlin he has that big gray beard he's tall he's like a
giant he is compared to the hobbit hobbits especially and his name is Gandalf the gray
Gandalf Gandalf and Gandalf has special powers as well he's a very powerful wizard and he's on
the side of good and he's kind of the guide for these little hobbits I think it's quite obvious
that he's on the side of the good people because he's wearing white clothes white symbolizes purity
yeah but the interesting thing is that Sauron is the opposite of him he's like his foil so
where Gandalf is good Sauron is the evil wizard and um there is one supreme evil being that's
like an eye that sees the land so Sauron is like this eye that is not really a person right it's
just like a power a power evil power right and and Sauron is basically the person or the entity
that wants the ring to again control all of middle earth that's right sure all right so it's
very interesting it sounds a little bit confusing but um it's a it's a very interesting story and
because it's so uh detail oriented and it has so many different angles and different races that
in the end come together that's why the movie as Gulan mentioned is pretty long I think it lasts
around two and a half hours yeah and it's only one of three so the whole movie is like
eight hours long right but it feels shorter than that and the the genre is fantasy so there
like you said there's a lot of stuff you have to learn about this world that you're in but
it's it's really beautifully well made it's really well made actors are amazing the music
special effects it was filmed in New Zealand right uh and it's gorgeous very beautiful scenery
and uh it's also very interesting all the all the different symbolisms that they take from
different mythology right well that's the interesting thing for me because J.R. Tolkien
was an expert in medieval history and in religion and literature from the age and so a lot of the
things he writes about he takes from human history right so yeah that that's really interesting
from what I understand it has a lot of Nordic influence as well and it's the characters in
general right and their names and their names they're very Nordic sounding and also this uh
language that the elves speak elvish elvish yeah I understand that also some very um
some fans of the movie are actually fluent in elvish uh that would not surprise me like
Klingon like Klingon from Star Wars all right so we actually have a clip from the movie it's the
pretty much the the beginning the introduction that explains what we just kind of talked about
about the origins of the ring why it exists and how it's how it came to be so dangerous right
yeah this is one of the elves who is telling us about the backstory the history of the ring and
how it got where it where it is today all right let's listen it began with the forging of the
great rings three were given to the elves immortal wisest and fairest of all beings
seven to the dwarf lords great miners and craftsmen of the mountain halls
and nine nine rings were gifted to the race of men who above all else desire power for within
these rings was bound the strength and will to govern each race but they were all of them
deceived for another ring was made in the land of mordor in the fires of mount duke the dark lord
sauna forged in secret a master ring to control all others and into this ring he poured his
cruelty his malice and his will to dominate all life one ring to rule them all by one
three lands of middle earth fell to the power of the ring who resisted a last alliance of men
and elves marched against the armies of mordor and on the slopes of mount doom they fought for
the freedom of middle earth all right we're back so that was interesting i can't remember this
does it make you want to watch the movie again it makes me want to watch the movie again it does
i actually watched it recently it reminds me of golem actually yeah your name kind of sounds
no i i like i like the character it was pretty good it was i thought it was this character is
is is corrupted by the ring right became all obsessed about it yeah i can't do it it hurts my
throat yeah he's totally obsessive he like it's the ring the ring has so much power over him
yeah yeah he he found it by by chance or he stole it from someone oh he and his friend find it one
day in a pond and then as soon as he puts it on or touches it the evil power just takes over him
he ends up killing his friend oh with him yeah at the time and he finds it and his old appearance
changes and his personality changes yeah he obsesses over the ring every time but actually the ring
gave him an extended life it's right he's like hundreds of years old i think yeah but then he's
all deformed and he's ugly and turned into this other creature i saw i saw this movie recently
about a month ago because i bought the dvds and i bought the director's cut so it was like the
extended version so it was three and a half hours long wow so um yeah it was really it was pretty
long but you didn't really feel the difference the extra hour because you saw some really cool
extra footage should i borrow it yeah i've never seen extended i think all the dvds all the dvds
come with them yeah they're actually each each set like the fellowship of the ring and the the
two towers yeah and then the last one what's called the return of the return of the king
the return of the king all of the all of them are two dvds so in mid-movie they actually say okay
please insert disc two because it's filmed in high definition and everything that's how i always did
i watched it in the theaters pretty long yeah all right so uh all in all gulam did you enjoy
the movie do you recommend it i do but there there's uh there's a side effect of your downside
once you start watching and you you will want to watch the next two movies immediately so you have
to set aside a good 10 hours or 12 hours of a weekend yeah like a weekend like you need a whole
day for that really true i agree that's how i feel i don't know is that what you did yeah
i had friends who watched them all one day they had a marathon yeah and you know what extended
version marathon wow and the worst thing is you keep doing it over and over also you re you watched
it again yeah well you had the whole marathon a couple of times you spent like literal days of
your life watching no it was it was more like i was the only guy who had the dvds and friends
would come over and as soon as they started watching and they just want to finish all like
finish watching the rest oh so you were pretty much yeah and i had to sit there and then i didn't
mind that i thought it was pretty okay all right what about you katherine you recommend the movie
absolutely i give it an a and um i think it's a modern classic it's beautifully shot the story is
brilliant i just everything about it is great it won many many awards right many awards rightfully
so although i have to admit of the series of the three the trilogy um my favorite is the two towers
i think it's the darkest of the three movies and i think it's just really gorgeous the way that
they have all the different shots we can talk about that another yeah we'll probably talk about
the two towers and the return of the king yep yeah um in different shows so but that's all for
today i hope you enjoyed this and we definitely recommend you go out by the dvd and watch this
movie if you haven't done so and if you have well it's pretty good to watch it again and as i said
watch the extended version is pretty interesting so let us know what you think did you give it an a
b c you didn't like it if you didn't like it why didn't you like it all right so uh we'll talk to
you guys next time and uh bye bye